# LEE LEMUS

Phone: (914) 826 3937 | Email: leelemus@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/leelemus

Address: 1302 Cherry Avenue, Madison, WI 53714

# **Summary**

Dynamic and resourceful Digital Marketing Expert with over 7 years of multi-industry and international experience in making brands connect with their customer. Very experienced in implementing strategies, tactics, and tools that address customer expectation, brand engagement, and business needs with multiple internal and external partners. A natural leader and relationship builder that enjoys working in the space where creative, digital, and analytics intersect.

## **Skills**

## **Digital / E-commerce Marketing**

Front End Design (HTML, CSS, JavaScript) CMS and DAM Administration Google Analytics PPC, SEO, SEM, and Display Optimization Digital Campaign Management Email Marketing

## **Social Media / Communications**

Social Media Management
Paid Social Optimization
Visual Content (Video and Photo)
Press Releases, Blog, and Copywriting
Public Speaking
Relationship Building

# Administrative / Other

Strategic Thinking
Team Management
Proactive Customer Service
Working with External & Internal Teams
International Sales & Marketing
Spanish Language Fluency

# **Work Experience**

#### DIGITAL ENGAGEMENT MARKETING MANAGER - Nasco International - Ft. Atkinson, WI - November 2016 - Present

- Playing a vital role in shaping the branding of four different industry verticals via digital channels.
- Created and implemented Social Media infrastructure and content strategy, resulting in +200% growth in engagement, +40% growth in web traffic acquisition, and ROAS of 5 to 1.
- Helped initiate, monitor, and optimize Affiliate program with external partners, maintaining a conversion rate of +15%.
- Restructured and managed digital creative team for improved efficiency and quality of content.
- Create and oversee execution of company-wide seasonal promotions and web merchandising, resulting in +5% increase in conversions.
- Played key role in email marketing strategy implementation and transition to new ESP, helping increase open and click-through rate by +10%.
- Work with creative and photography teams to create imagery and video that is relevant and inspiring to target audiences.
- Conducted content audits for transition to new ecommerce web platform.
- Work with the Merchandising department in identifying featured products, trends, events, and stories.
- Maintain and monitor relationships with agencies running Affiliate, PPC, and Display advertising.
- Research and analyze trends, events, tools, and solutions that can positively impact each vertical of the business.
- Managing budget for maximum ROI.

## MARKETING & COMMUNICATIONS MANAGER - Trek Bicycle Corporation - Waterloo, WI - July 2011 - March 2016

- Positioned Trek and Bontrager to be the number one high end cycling brand in Mexico.
- Consistently maintained web traffic growth of at least 25% year over year.
- Drove B2B online sales to be 55% of total yearly sales.
- Created social media page with reach and engagement growth of over 40% year over year.
- Increased email newsletter list by 30% with click through rates of at least 15% year over year.
- Created and led Ride Camp, a best practice event for all global markets.
- Was the voice and producer of all Spanish language content in western hemisphere markets.
- Initiated, nurtured, and leveraged relationships of all types to the brands' advantage.
- Attracted, sponsored, and worked with the best athletes and events in the market.
- Planned, controlled, and leveraged budget for maximum ROI.

# ONLINE MARKETING MANAGER - Tech Alliance - New York, NY - June 2009 - May 2011

- Boosted lead quantity and quality by 100% by revamping marketing message and strategy.
- Personally redesigned web site for optimal SEO, AdWord, and Analytics performance.
- Created engaging and purposeful content for marketing and sales.
- Maintained great relationships and provided great customer service to clients.

## WEB DESIGN & PRODUCTION ASSOCIATE - WebMD - New York, NY - September 2008 - June 2009

- Produced standards compliant HTML and XML content.
- Enforced coding, styling, grammatical, data, and graphical standards.
- Increased article submission rate by 25%.

# ONLINE MARKETING MANAGER - Brickhouse Security - New York, NY - September 2007 - September 2008

- Oversaw web and marketing projects to increase brand awareness and sales.
- Continually optimized performance of web and print advertising.
- Manage dynamic group of web, graphic, and marketing people.

## WEB DEVELOPER & GRAPHIC DESIGNER - Kuma Reality Games - New York, NY - March 2007 - September 2007

- Developed, designed and optimized user interface of games.
- Optimized web sites for SEO rankings.

## **Education**

BACHELORS IN COMPUTER INFORMATION SYSTEMS - DeVry Institute of Technology - New York, NY - 1999 - 2002